(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-12T00:18:27.848524",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
灼けつくような陽射し
A scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water's surface.
燥ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Behind the frolicking summer colors and backlight,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
it brings back the memories of our youth.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the hem of my denim jeans,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sand.
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning around the edge of the glass,
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
are shining lapis lazuli marbles.
なんだか その笑顔と紙一重だ
Somehow, it's a paper-thin line from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
If you look through the film, it's non-fiction,
彩りに絆されたメモリー
a memory bound by colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because there's no resetting it.
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
inside the algorithm.
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
capturing every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love.
二度と忘れないように
So we never forget it again.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の想い出
a lifetime of memories with you.
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
灼けつくような陽射し
A scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water's surface.
燥ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Behind the frolicking summer colors and backlight,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
it brings back the memories of our youth.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the hem of my denim jeans,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sand.
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning around the edge of the glass,
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
are shining lapis lazuli marbles.
なんだか その笑顔と紙一重だ
Somehow, it's a paper-thin line from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
If you look through the film, it's non-fiction,
彩りに絆されたメモリー
a memory bound by colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because there's no resetting it.
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
inside the algorithm.
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
capturing every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love.
二度と忘れないように
So we never forget it again.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の想い出
a lifetime of memories with you.
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
As the ice melts, it swirls,
魔法の杖がわりのマドラー
the stirrer acting as a magic wand.
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickles the back of my throat,
香る柑橘系のフレイバー
with the aroma of citrus flavor.
爽やかな気流にのって
Riding on the refreshing breeze,
波の還りを見守ってる beachside
watching the waves return from the beachside.
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Yearning for that innocent look,
微かに触れそうな指先
our fingertips are almost touching.
煌めきで上塗りしてしまおう
Let's paint over it with sparkles.
get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
inside the algorithm.
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
capturing every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love.
二度と忘れないように
So we never forget it again.
ミッドサマーシトラス oh yeah
Midsummer citrus, oh yeah,
いつだって we got love !! okay
we always have love, okay?
キミといるだけで
Just being with you,
feel so nice ココロはまた実り
feels so nice, my heart blooms again.
寝起きの太陽も
The waking sun is also
願ってもない燦々日和？
an unexpectedly radiant day, right?
白飛びしてしまうほど
So bright it almost overexposes,
眩しいのは夏のせい
the dazzling brightness is all because of summer.
躍ってミッドサマー
Dance, midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中 (ooh)
in the algorithm (Ooh).
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in the blink of an eye,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
capturing all our emotions.
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
This must be love (Ooh),
二度と忘れないように
so we'll never forget it again.
(Ok)
Le Lemon Lime Orange
Le-Lemon Lime Orange,
キミと一生分の想い出
a lifetime of memories with you.
(Ok)
何気ない一日が One of a kind
An ordinary day becomes one of a kind.
うわー！
Wow!
はーい！じゃあ、まずは挨拶からいきましょう！
Alright! First, let's start with our greeting!
せーの、Reach the top!
One, two, Reach the top!
We are ReGLOSS!
よっしゃ、これで自己紹介やろう！
Alright, let's do our self-introductions!
はい！フームフームフーム、ホロライブデバイス、リグロス、歌が大好きな、
Yes! Hum, hum, hum! Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS, the music-loving,
奏でること、音乃瀬奏でーす！こんにちは！
singing and playing Kanade, Otonose Kanade here! Hello!
そして！
And next!
はい！ポジティブジーニアス！ホロライブデバイス、リグロスの一条莉々華だよ！イェーイ！
Yes! Positive genius! Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's Ichijou Ririka here! Yay!
そして！
And next!
えー、ブンブンブン！ホロライブデバイス、リグロスの、轟はじめ、始まりまーす！そして！
Uh, Vroom vroom vroom! Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's Todoroki Hajime, starting now! And next!
はい！ホロライブデバイス、リグロスの人間国宝、トーク担当、儒烏風亭、お前は？全然みだらーい！儒烏風亭らでんでございます！
Yes! Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's Living National Treasure, Talk Representative. Juufuutei, are you...? "Not at all lewd!" Juufuutei Raden here!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いきなりでしたから、なんと新曲を披露させていただきました！イェーイ！
Out of nowhere, we just performed our new song! Yay!
みんな、どうだった？どうだったー？
How was it, everyone? How was it?
最初のさ...
At the beginning...
本当にごめんなさい！本当にごめんなさい！本当に申し訳ない！
I'm so sorry! I'm really sorry! I'm truly sorry!
もう最初さ...
From the very beginning...
最初ね、あの、これ、ぜひアーカイブで見返してほしいんですけども、
At the beginning, I really want you to rewatch it in the archive,
我々があの、足でじゃんけんをするっていう...
but we were supposed to do rock-paper-scissors with our feet...
そう、あの「あっち向いてホイ」をするシーンがあるんだよね。
Yeah, there's a scene where we do "Look That Way, Hoi."
そう、そこで、あの、事前の打ち合わせと、あの、違うものが出てしまって...
Yeah, and there, something different from our rehearsal came out...
違うものが出てしまった！
Something completely different came out!
しかも、1回あっち向いてホイ、成功しなかったけど、なんか、莉々華が勝ったことになってて...
And even though the "Look That Way, Hoi" didn't succeed the first time, somehow it was decided that Ririka won...
莉々華も笑ってるし、みんな笑ってるし！
Ririka was laughing, everyone was laughing!
でも、ソロパート頑張んなきゃって思ったら、声がめっちゃ震えてた！
But then I had to do my solo part, and my voice was shaking so much!
みんなに笑い声聞こえちゃってたのかな？
I wonder if everyone heard the laughter?
聞こえちゃってた！コメント欄見えて、笑ってるやん、ってなった。
They totally did! I saw the comments saying, "They're laughing!"
そう、実はね、そんなこんながあったんです。けれど、まあ、そんな困難もね、生配信、ライブの醍醐味でございます！
Yes, actually, all that happened. But well, those kind of mishaps are the real charm of live streams and live performances!
そうですね。1回目だからバレてないやろ？ああいうものだと思われてるかもしれない。
That's true. It's the first time, so maybe they didn't realize? They might think it was meant to be like that.
バレる、バレる！
No way, they'll know!
はい、ということで、こんな「ミッドサマーシトラス」なんですが、なんと、もうすでにね、MVが公開されております！
Yes! And speaking of "Midsummer Citrus," the music video has actually already been released!
イェーイ！見てくれたかな？見た？見た？
Yay! Did you watch it? Did you? Did you?
せっかくなのでね、一人ずつ感想聞いていきますか？じゃあ、ここから、ばんちょーから！
Since we're here, shall we hear everyone's thoughts one by one? Let's start with Bancho!
えー、なんか、やっぱ、夏って言ったら、こう、ハッピー、ハッピーって感じなのかなって思ったら、
Well, you'd think summer would be all "happy happy,"
ちょっとこう、ノスタルジックな、ちょっとエモい感じの、過去を彷彿とさせる、良い夏の思い出、みたいな感じで、
but this has a nostalgic, kind of emotional feel that brings back past memories of a great summer,
エモい、良い曲だなって思ってます！
so I think it's a really emotional, beautiful song!
いいよねー！いいこと言うじゃん！
That's so nice! Well said!
奏は？
How about Kanade?
えー、奏は、やっぱりこう、制服着てたりしてたから、学生時代のことをやっぱり思い出したりしたし、
Well, for me, since we wore school uniforms in it, it really made me remember my student days,
あと、すごい爽やかな夏曲だったから、外に出てね、暑い夏の時に外に出て、
and it's a super refreshing summer song, so going out on a hot summer day,
聴きながら道を歩いてたら涼しくなるのかなと思いました！
and walking around listening to it might make you feel cooler!
いっぱい聴いてください！
Please listen to it a lot!
莉々華はね、なんか、MVにやっぱり私たちのカット、青くんのも含めてね、リグロスのカットがたくさん入ってて、
For me, the music video has so many cuts of us, including Ao-kun's, so many ReGLOSS cuts,
なんかそれを見てるだけでちょっとニヤニヤしちゃった。私たちのなのに！
and just watching it made me grin. Even though it's of us!
奏、すごい莉々華が色気づいてるところ隣で見てた...
Kanade, you were watching Ririka acting all flirtatious right next to her...
こうやって、こうやって見つめてた。
I was staring at her like this, like this.
でも、よくやってる、それは。
But you do that a lot.
奏もね、莉々華のことガン見してるから、あ、再現されてるなーと思って。
Kanade also stares intently at Ririka, so I thought, "Ah, they recreated that perfectly."
再現されてるそうです！なので色々ね、ちょっと細かいところぜひ皆さんも見てみてください！
Apparently, it's recreated! So please check out all the little details, everyone!
みてください！
Please do!
そして、あの、このね、サビの冒頭、「躍ってミッドサマー」ってある通り、
And also, just like the beginning of the chorus goes "Dance, midsummer,"
こういうところとかね、みんなで「ウォウウォウウォウウォウ」って言うところとか、
parts like this, where we all go "woah, woah, woah,"
すごくノリやすくて、踊りやすい曲なんじゃないかなと思いますので、ぜひ皆さんも踊ってミッドサマーやってください！
make it a super catchy and easy song to dance to. So please, everyone, try dancing and do "midsummer"!
ということで、今回のね、MVに関わってくださった監督、クリエイターの皆様、素敵に撮影してくださって本当にありがとうございました！
So, to the director and all the creators who worked on this MV, thank you so much for capturing us so beautifully!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
そして、ついに！ついに！
And finally! Finally!
明日0時、つまり、今日の24時に、こちらね、ミッドサマーシトラス、デジタルリリースされます！イェーイ！
Tomorrow at 0:00, which means at 24:00 tonight, "Midsummer Citrus" will be digitally released! Yay!
だから、日付が変わったタイミングですね。リグロスといえばお馴染みの...
So, right when the date changes. And speaking of ReGLOSS...
おとらさん、前島想己さんに手掛けていただいた
Written by Otora-san and Soki Maeshima-san,
爽やかなメロディーと心地良いリズムが
the refreshing melody and pleasant rhythm...
夏の暑さを吹き飛ばしてくれるような一曲でございます！
make this a song that will blow away the summer heat!
ぜひこの夏は『Midsummer Citrus』を聴いて
This summer, please listen to "Midsummer Citrus"
ReGLOSSとの夏の思い出をたくさん作りましょう！
and make plenty of summer memories with ReGLOSS!
作りましょう！
Let's make some!
いぇーい！
Yay!
あちゅ、あちゅ...
It's so hot...
ということで、今日はね、ここからまた別の夏曲を歌っていこうと思うんですけれども
And so, we're going to sing another summer song from here today,
事前にね、アンケートでみんなにね、応募してもらった曲も歌いますので、楽しみにしていてください！
but we'll also sing the songs you requested in the survey, so look forward to it!
いぇーい！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
じゃあちょっとね、真夏のビーチということで、あまりにも暑くて倒れてしまいそうなので、移動しますか！
Now, since it's a midsummer beach and it's so hot we might collapse, shall we move?
移動しましょう！
Let's move!
これ、あの、あれやらなくていいの？
Wait, shouldn't we do that thing?
何、何？
What thing?
あちゅ、あちゅ、あちゅ、あちゅ...
Hot, hot, hot, hot...
あ、そうだった！そうだった！あちゅ、あちゅ、あちゅ、あちゅ、あちゅ！あちゅい！
Oh, right! Right! Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot! It's hot!
強制カットやって！おーい！
A forced cut! Hey!
じゃ、行きましょうかね
Well, shall we go?
はーい、どこ行こうかね？
Okay, where should we go?
やっちまった...
I messed up...
何やっちまったんだっけ？いけるいける！
What did you mess up? You're fine, you're fine!
何もやっちまってないよ！大丈夫だよ
You didn't mess up anything! It's okay.
じゃあカラオケ向かいますか
Shall we head to karaoke then?
カラオケ行こ、行こ！カラオケ！
Let's go to karaoke! Karaoke!
カラオケ行くにょ？
We're going to karaoke?
カラオケって言ったら歌うんだからね！
If we go to karaoke, we're definitely singing!
歌うならやっぱカラオケっしょ！
If you want to sing, karaoke is the place!
会員証持ってる？
Do you have your membership card?
会員証持ってるよ！
I have it!
あ,アプリ、アプリダウンロードしてないかも...
Oh, I might not have downloaded the app...
あ、ていうかカードで持ってるから大丈夫
Oh, actually, I have the physical card, so it's fine.
カード！渋いな！
A card! How old-school!
えー、夏、何を歌おうかな？
Hmm, what summer song should we sing?
えー、悩むね！
Yeah, it's hard to decide!
今回はリクエストをね、いただいておりますから
We received requests this time,
ありがたい！みんなのリクエスト！
That's great! Everyone's requests!
もしかしたら選ばれるかもしれない
so your request might be chosen.
『Midsummer Citrus』？それは歌ったって！さっき歌ったのよ、それ
"Midsummer Citrus"? We already sang that! We just sang it!
それ歌ったじゃん
We literally just sang that.
じゃあ、じゃんけんのやり直し？
Then, shall we redo the rock-paper-scissors?
じゃんけん！じゃんけん！
Rock-paper-scissors!
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！あいこでしょ！あいこでしょ！
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot! One more time! One more time!
いいところでやるな！
Don't cut it at the best part!
続くような日々さ...
Like days that would go on...
あ、カラオケ着いた！着いた着いた！
Ah, we arrived at karaoke! We're here!
あ、すごいポスターあるじゃん！
Oh, there's an amazing poster!
ポスター？あ、パスタね
A poster? Ah, pasta.
パスタ？急にパスタ出てきた、パスタ
Pasta? Suddenly pasta came up.
カラオケにパスタあるわけないじゃん！
There's no way there's pasta in a karaoke room!
ないね！じゃあ座りましょうか
True! Well, let's sit down.
ちょっとドリンクバー行ってくるけど、なんかいる？
I'm going to the drink bar, do you want anything?
えー、じゃあ、コーンスープ！
Hmm, then corn soup!
コーンスープ？
Corn soup?
りりか、コーンスープと、あとカルピス2個欲しい
I'll have corn soup, and also two Calpis.
えー、じゃあ奏はウーロン茶！
Then I'll have oolong tea!
ウーロン茶。じゃあ、全部に、上にソフトクリームつけて
Oolong tea. Then, put soft-serve ice cream on top of all of them.
なんでだよ！ドリンクバーにのせられないよ
Why?! You can't put that on top at a drink bar!
あ、そっかそっか。戻らなくちゃ
Oh, right. I should head back.
じゃあね、時間もないので、早速歌っていこうと思います！
Well, since we don't have much time, let's start singing!
いやー、何の歌を歌うのかな？楽しみだね
Man, I wonder what song we'll sing? I'm excited.
ねー
Yeah.
一番最初に歌いたい人、誰ですか？
Who wants to sing first?
はい！
Me!
お、番長！
Oh, Banchou!
行くじゃん！『Midsummer Citrus』であんだけ歌って踊った後に、一発目この元気よさで行ける人なかなかいないよ
Not many people can be this energetic right after singing and dancing so much to "Midsummer Citrus".
さすが番長！
As expected of Banchou!
もうね、夏、盛り上げていこうじゃん！
Let's liven up the summer!
いぇーい！じゃあ、番長からいきましょう！
Yay! Alright, let's start with Banchou!
よろしくお願いします！
Please enjoy!
はい！ワン、ツー...
Yeah! One, two...
番長がんばれー！いぇーい！
Go for it, Banchou! Yay!
テンション上がる！
This gets me pumped up!
いぇーい！
Yay!
「サンオイル 背中に塗って！」と
"Put some tanning oil on my back!" she said,
水着の上 外しながら 寝そべった
as she unclasped her swimsuit top and lay down.
大胆な 君の一言は
Those bold words of yours...
甘ったるい 匂いがした
...had a sweet fragrance.
僕は一人泳いだよ
I swam all alone.
あと その後のいきなりのキスは
And then, that sudden kiss afterward...
塩辛い味がした
...tasted salty.
さっきまでのあの風景とは
Compared to the scenery from just a moment ago,
空気まで変わった気がする
...even the air itself felt like it had changed.
海と空がちゃんと向き合って
The sea and the sky face each other properly,
そうお互いのその青さ
Yes, reflecting each other's...
映し合っている
...blue.
渚のGood job! 愛しい人よ
Good job on the beach, my beloved!
ずっと切なくて言えなかった
I couldn't say it because it was too painful,
君が近すぎて
you were too close.
きっかけGood job!
Good job, this chance!
素直になるんだ
I'm going to be honest with myself.
手を伸ばそう
Let's reach out our hands,
恋の季節じゃないか!
isn't this the season of love!
真夏のSounds good!
Summer sounds good!
つぶやきながら
As I whisper it...
次のステップへ進みたいね
I want to take the next step,
恋のカリキュラム
our love curriculum.
波音Sounds good!
The sound of the waves sounds good!
心が騒ぐよ
My heart is racing!
去年よりも
More than last year,
僕は本気になる
I am getting serious.
真夏のSounds good!
Summer sounds good!
君が好きだ
I love you!
波音Sounds good!
The sound of the waves sounds good!
やっと言えたよ
I finally said it.
渚のGood job!
Good job on the beach!
君が好きだ
I love you!
きっかけGood job!
Good job, this chance!
いいタイミングだね
It's perfect timing, isn't it?
真夏のSounds good!
Summer sounds good!
1曲目からぶち上がっていく！
Getting hyped up right from the first song!
おっしゃ、おっしゃ、おっしゃ！
Alright, alright, alright!
良い曲ですね
That's a great song.
なんか炒め物ビートを貰ってるらしく...
Apparently, I've got a stir-fry beat going on...
炒め物ビート？おっさんみたいなのしようとしてる？
Stir-fry beat? Are you trying to act like a middle-aged guy?
ちょっと何かおっさんを入れたい、今
I want to channel a bit of a middle-aged guy right now.
おっさんを入れたい？
Channel a middle-aged guy?
ちょっとキラキラしすぎてて、今...
Because I was being a bit too sparkly just now...
ちなみに何でさ、この曲にしたの？青ちゃん
By the way, why did you choose this song, Ao-chan?
え、なんかアンケートにあって、歌えるでチェックを入れた
Well, it was on a survey, so I checked 'can sing'.
もうちょっとあるでしょ！こういうところが好きで、とか
There's got to be more than that! Like 'I like this part' or something!
いや、でも、すごいじゃん。白い砂浜、青い空
No, but think about it. White beaches, blue skies...
白いビキニの美少女たちが、キャーってやってる姿が浮かび上がるのが、すごく素敵じゃないですか
and beautiful girls in white bikinis squealing... Isn't it wonderful how that image comes to mind?
なるほどね！
I see!
楽しい曲だし、盛り上がるね。初めて聴いたんだけど
It's a fun, hype song. It was my first time hearing it,
すごい、もうノリノリだった今
but I was totally grooving to it.
楽しかった
It was fun!
ダンスも準備してきたの？
Did you prepare the dance, too?
いや、ノリ
No, it was just on the spot.
本家のダンスは別にあって、それはごめんなさい、覚えてきてないですけど
There is an official dance, but sorry, I didn't memorize it.
でも即興でやったってことだよね？
But that means you improvised all of that just now, right?
ノリで
Just went with the flow.
すごーい！青ちゃんありがとう
Amazing! Thanks, Ao-chan.
ウェーブとかやばかった
That wave was incredible.
青ちゃんに拍手を！ありがとう！
A round of applause for Ao-chan! Thank you!
次、じゃあ次どうする？
Next, what should we do next?
この後歌いたい人いるわけないじゃん！
There's no way anyone wants to sing after that!
なんでー！？
Why not?!
でも一応、台本だと奏になってるけど
Well, according to the script, Kanade is up next...
うるさーい！
Shut up!
がんばれ、奏！
Good luck, Kanade!
奏、準備大丈夫？
Kanade, are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ、いこう！
Alright, let's go!
音楽おねがいします！
Music, please!
いつものあれ、ください
Give me the usual.
本能が狂い始める
Instinct begins to go wild
追い詰められたハツカネズミ
A cornered mouse
今、絶望の淵に立って
Now, standing on the brink of despair
踏切へと飛び出した
Leaping towards the railroad crossing
そう 君は友達
Yes, you are my friend
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand
居場所なんて無いだろ
You have no place to belong, right?
二人きりこのまま
Just the two of us like this,
愛し合えるさー
we can love each other...
繰り返す
Repeating,
フラッシュバック・蝉の声
the flashbacks, the cicadas' voices...
二度とは帰らぬ君
You, who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく
Torn apart for eternity,
お揃いのキーホルダー
our matching keychains.
夏が消し去った
Summer has erased
白い肌の少女に
the white-skinned girl.
哀しい程
To a heartbreaking extent,
とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be completely possessed by her.
うわー！最高！ありがとう！
Wow! That was the best! Thank you!
すごい！
Amazing!
ふぅー！
Woohoo!
本性が暴れ始める
True instincts start running wild,
九月のスタート
at the start of September,
告げるチャイム
announced by the chime.
次の標的に置かれた花瓶
The vase placed for the next target...
仕掛けたのは僕だった
The one who set it up was me.
そう 君が悪いんだよ
Yes, it is your fault.
僕だけを見ててよ
Look only at me.
そう 君の苦しみ
Yes, your suffering...
助けが欲しいだろ
You want to be saved, right?
溺れてく其の手に
To those drowning hands,
そっと口吻(kiss)をしたー。
I gently gave a kiss...
薄笑いの獣たち
The sneering beasts,
その心晴れるまで
until their hearts clear up,
爪を突き立てる
they dig in their claws.
不揃いのスカート
Our mismatched skirts.
夏の静寂を
The summer silence,
切り裂くような悲鳴が
shattered by a scream,
こだまする教室の窓には青空
echoes in the classroom. Out the window is a blue sky.
なんかお揃いやってる
They are doing matching moves.
ひとりふりきりやってる
One person is completely going for it.
あそこ！
Right there!
あ、黄色だからあっち
Oh, it's yellow, so it's that way.
きみ、あたま...！
Your head...!
そう 君は友達
Yes, you are my friend.
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab onto my hand.
そう 君が居なくちゃ
Yes, if you aren't here,
居場所なんて無いんだよ
there is no place to belong.
透き通った世界で
In a transparent world,
愛し合えたらー。
if only we could love each other...
繰り返す
Repeating,
フラッシュバック・蝉の声・
the flashbacks, the cicadas' voices...
二度とは帰らぬ君
You, who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく
Torn apart for eternity,
お揃いのキーホルダー
our matching keychains.
夏が消し去った
Summer has erased
白い肌の少女に
the white-skinned girl.
哀しい程
To a heartbreaking extent,
とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be completely possessed by her.
透明な君は
The transparent you
僕を指差してたー。
was pointing at me...
ふぅー！かっこいい！すごい！
Woohoo! So cool! Amazing!
ありがとうございます。少女レイでしたー！
Thank you very much. That was Shoujo Rei!
一気にエモい気分になったわー。
I suddenly got into such an emotional mood!
奏の、あの綺麗なさ、透き通るような声にめちゃくちゃ合ってる、これ。
This really suits Kanade's beautiful, transparent voice!
うれしい！歌えて嬉しい！
I'm so glad! I'm happy I got to sing it!
コメントでもね、奏に、ぜひ奏に歌ってほしいっていうのがあったみたいだよ。
It seems there were comments saying they really wanted Kanade to sing it too.
センス良い！コメントした人、最高！
Great taste! The person who commented is the best!
そのコメントした人！
That person who commented!
奏の後は、奏の後で相当なプレッシャー...緊張するんですけども。
Following Kanade is a lot of pressure... I'm so nervous.
じゃあ、帰りますね。
Well, I'm going home then.
帰らないで！お疲れ様でしたけど、まだ帰らないで！
Don't go home! Good job, but don't leave yet!
もう今、奏に選ばれてちょっとドキドキしてるし。
Now I'm getting a bit fluttery from being chosen by Kanade.
選ばれたんならさ、次は...次は選ばれた方の...私じゃないですか？
If you were chosen, then next... wouldn't the next one chosen be me?
がんばって歌います！おー！行けー！
I'll do my best to sing! Oh! Go for it!
楽しく歌おう！楽しみにゃ！
Let's sing happily! Excited-nya!
うん、じゃあ行きます。お願いします！
Yeah, okay, here I go. Please start!
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, flickering,
蒼き夢舞い放つ
a blue dream fired into the sky,
花燃えゆく
a burning flower.
懐かしい曲！大好き、この曲！
Nostalgic song! I love this song!
静寂に落ちる空
In the silently falling sky,
ふたひらの夢花火
two dream fireworks.
彼方に旅立つ
As you journeyed far away,
あなたも見えたの？ 同じ
could you also see the same...
光が
...light?
離れてもいつの日か
Though we are apart, someday...
出逢えると信じてる
...I believe we'll meet again.
胸裂く想いをあなたに
As I sing of this heartrending love to you,
歌うわ声が聴こえる？
can you hear my voice?
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for an instant, that's fireworks.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, flickering,
蒼き夢舞い放つ
a blue dream fired into the sky,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
blooming high in the distance.
守りゆくその想い
I'll protect that love earnestly...
ひたすら鳴り響け
...as it reverberates.
果てるまでせめて強く
Let it be strong til the end,
此の花 燃えゆく
this burning flower.
いくつもの言の葉を
So many words...
悪戯に散らかした
...scattered teasingly.
断ちゆく迷いは
Cut off, the hesitation...
静かに消えたの
...quietly disappeared.
明日が見えてる？
Can you see tomorrow?
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for an instant, that's fireworks.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, flickering,
つかみゆく幻の花
we can grab this dream flower...
あたしの手を零れ落ちて
...spilling from my hand.
願うままこの想い
I just wish this love...
あなたに鳴り渡れ
...will echo to you.
果てるならせめて強く
Let it be strong til the end,
此の花 燃えゆく
this burning flower.
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for an instant, that's fireworks.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, flickering,
蒼き夢舞い上がれ
a blue dream soaring high.
いつの日かめぐり逢えて
Someday we'll meet again.
繋ぎゆくこの想い
This love connects...
愛しき君 我
...you and me,
いつまでも双片 強く
forever strong, the two of us.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, flickering,
蒼き夢舞い放つ
a blue dream fired into the sky,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
blooming high in the distance.
守りゆくその想い
I'll protect that love earnestly...
ひたすら鳴り響け
...as it reverberates.
果てるまでせめて強く
Let it be strong til the end,
此の花 燃えゆく
this burning flower.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃ良かった！/ 嬉しい！
That was so good! / I'm so happy!
すごいなんか莉々華に合ってるよね、この曲 / めっちゃ合ってる！
This song really suits Ririka, doesn't it? / It totally does!
え、めっちゃ嬉しい！これすごい大好きなアニメの、BLEACHのアニメの曲なんだけど
Really? I'm so glad! This is a song from an anime I really love, BLEACH.
あ、そうなーんだ / そう、いっぱい聴いてた曲だったから、歌いたかったの
Oh, is that so? / Yeah, I used to listen to it a lot, so I really wanted to sing it.
いいじゃん、いいじゃん / 嬉しかった
That's awesome! / I'm glad.
でも、ってことは次は、らでんちゃんの番！
But that means next up is Raden-chan's turn!
え？ 番？
What? My turn?
ちみだよ！ 番？
You! My turn?
じゃあちょっと、ここでまた盛り上がる系の曲をいこうかなと思います！
Then, I think I'll perform another high-energy song here!
おお！ 最高！
Oh! Awesome!
さあ、チャトラの皆さん、ENJOYの準備をお願いします！
Now, everyone in the chat, get ready to "ENJOY"!
ENJOY！
ENJOY!
それではいきましょう！準備OKですか？
Here we go! Are you ready?
いきましょう！ココロオドル！みんな、一緒に盛り上がってください！
Here we go! Kokoro Odoru! Everyone, let's get hyped together!
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps on playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, I want to deliver this heartbeat
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす
My heart dances, causing an encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し
Right now, going further than crossing the finish line
音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Riding on the sound, keeping on swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep on echoing
のってきな的な言葉が出てきた
Groovy words have come out
ここは心躍るところだから
Because this is where the heart dances
置いてかないよ 追い付きたいなら
I won't leave you behind, so if you want to keep up
Get Up Stand Up 行くしかねぇ
Get Up, Stand Up, we've gotta go
つかねぇやっぱ気付いたんだ 100%
Anyway, I definitely realized it 100%
幸せの意思表示 鳴らせ CLAP CLAP
An expression of happiness, sound the CLAP CLAP
仲間同士 夜通し 詰め込んだ
Among friends, packed all through the night
Have a dreamin' グリーディング
Have a dreamin' greeting
この場の空気 中心
The atmosphere of this place, the center
サークル 繋がるブギー
The circle connects the boogie
フリーキー気張らずここのみんなと
Freaky, relaxed, with everyone here
その価値あるから Swing swing sing a song
Because it's worth it, Swing swing sing a song
生真面目 恥ずかしがりでもできる
Even those who are serious and shy can do it
イマジネーション 望むところだ
Imagination, just what we wanted
茶の間 床の間 ところ構わず
Living room, alcove, anywhere, no matter where
ボタンひとつで踊る心が
With just one button, the heart dances
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps on playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸 of 鼓動
IT'S JOIN, I want to deliver this heartbeat
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす
My heart dances, causing an encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し
Right now, going further than crossing the finish line
音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Riding on the sound, keeping on swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep on echoing
やっぱりな Hurry up 俺は急いで歯を磨く
As I thought, Hurry up, I quickly brush my teeth
手間は取らせん さぁ見な
I won't waste your time, now watch
あみ出すっつうか 勝手 心騒ぎ出す
Spinning it out, or rather, my heart starts racing of its own accord
時間 場所など限らず
Without limits on time or place
グータラ てきぱき 日常 メリハリ
Lazy or brisk, daily life with modulation
毎日変わる音 フレッシュ デリバリー
Music that changes daily, fresh delivery
揺らす Body Rock 増々
Shaking it, Body Rock, more and more
ベクトル向かう矢先はプラスへ
The direction the vector heads is toward the plus side
その長と短 そこがどうかなる
Its merits and faults, what will become of them?
所々 ココロゴト 転がしあう
Here and there, rolling our hearts together
だから今日は今日は振り切る昨日
So today, today we shake off yesterday
心から躍らす この一時
Making the heart dance from the inside out, this moment
一度 Go ドア開けたらフロア
Once you Go and open the door, it's the floor
浮き足立つ 抜け出す 揺れる Core
Feeling restless, escaping, shaking Core
Up and down こっち タンタ タップ レッツ ダンス
Up and down here, tap-tap, let's dance
Come on 加速 構うもんかもう
Come on, acceleration, what do I care anymore?
いてもたってもいらんない 心だけじゃ収まんないぜ
Can't sit still, my heart alone can't contain it
Day and Night Shake a body
ぎこちないならしないで 可愛い心感じるままに
If it's awkward, don't do it, just feel with your cute heart
LA LA LA LIVE LIVE GOOD TO BE ALIVE
笑い 愛し合いされ 喜怒哀楽 刻む
Laughing, loving and being loved, carving our emotions
音と言葉 つなぐこの場
Connecting sound and words in this place
届いてるなら MAKE SOME NOISE
If you can hear it, MAKE SOME NOISE
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps on playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, I want to deliver this heartbeat
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす
My heart dances, causing an encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し
Right now, going further than crossing the finish line
音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Riding on the sound, keeping on swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep on echoing
すごい！ 激熱！
Amazing! So hyped!
やばい！
Crazy!
めっちゃかっこいい！
So cool!
束の間の休憩
A brief rest
グレートフル 絵描く
Grateful, drawing a picture
スケールはでかく 楽しいもんだ エラくデラックス
The scale is grand, it's so much fun, super deluxe
狙う暇なんか単純に簡単
Time to aim is simply easy
預けてカウントダウン 3・2・1
Entrust it, countdown 3, 2, 1
なりふり構わず 夢中で駆け抜けろ
Without worrying about appearances, run through in a daze
息巻いて It's like this
Breathing hard, It's like this
さらに深い感動へ モーレツ oh yes
To an even deeper emotion, fiercely, oh yes
ココロオドル 今日へ
To today, my heart dances
さあ、最後！サビです！チャトラの皆さん、ラストも盛り上がっていきましょう！
Alright, the last chorus! Everyone in the chat, let's keep getting hyped until the end!
（今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける）
(Right now, going further than crossing the finish line, riding on the sound, keeping on swimming)
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps on playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, I want to deliver this heartbeat
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす
My heart dances, causing an encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し
Right now, going further than crossing the finish line
音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Riding on the sound, keeping on swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep on echoing
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす
My heart dances, causing an encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し
Right now, going further than crossing the finish line
音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Riding on the sound, keeping on swimming
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Responding hearts keep on echoing
イェーーイ！
Yeeaah!
最高！
Awesome!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
らでん！ らでん！
Raden! Raden!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
かっこいい！
So cool!
最高！
Awesome!
心踊ったわ
My heart danced.
うん、楽しい曲だ
Yeah, it's a fun song.
1人ですぐ歌う曲ではないよな
Not really a song to sing alone, though!
それは本当にそう！でもすごい！
That's so true! But you were amazing!
すごかった、歌い切ったよ
You were great, you sang it all!
すごいエネルギー感じたよ、今
I felt so much energy just now!
もう歌えない？
Can't you sing anymore?
いやいや、まだ1周しかしてないですけど
No, no, we've only gone around once!
はあー、じゃあどうする？
Whew, so what's next?
さあ、次誰歌う？
Okay, who's singing next?
次、会長に歌うか！
Next, should the President sing?
えええええ！ / えええ！？
Eeeeh?! / What?!
何だろう。いいよ。じゃあ番長のセンスに任せるわ。
I wonder what it'll be. Sure, I'll leave it to Bancho's taste.
私のセンスで？おっけおっけ！
With my taste? Okay, okay!
おっけー！じゃあ準備おっけ？うん！
Okay! Are you ready? Yep!
はい！
Yes!
お願いしまーす！
Let's do this!
イケナイ太陽
[Title: Ikenai Taiyou]
Hoo...
イケナイ太陽
The bad sun...
Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na
チョットでいいから
Just for a moment,
みせてくれないか
won't you show me?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンで
With your sexy pheromones,
オレ メロメロ
I'm head over heels.
Ah ふれちゃいそう
Ah, it feels like I'm going to touch you,
でも イケナイの！
but I shouldn't!
徐々に高鳴る鼓動
Little by little, my heart beats faster,
止められないわ
I can't stop it.
交わす言葉の記憶遠く
Memories of the words we exchange fade away,
口元の動きに揺れ動く
wavering with the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then, ah...
ABC 続かない
We can't even get past ABC.
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
That's no good, is it?
だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
オレの青春
My youth
そんなもんじゃない
is not just some trivial thing.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn hot deep inside.
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it.
オレは イケナイ太陽
I am the bad sun.
Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na
ハッ、ハッ、ハッ！ / ここ合ってるでしょ？ / あはは！
Ha, ha, ha! / We got this part right, didn't we? / Ahaha!
「赤い糸」なんて 絵空事
The "red thread of fate" is just a fantasy,
でも下心でさえ信じたいの
but I want to believe even in your ulterior motives.
俺は正しい キミも正しい
I'm right, and you're right.
とにかくもう 左右されないぜ
Anyway, I won't be swayed anymore.
騙し騙され胸うずく
Deceiving and being deceived makes my heart ache.
下手な芝居が より盛り上げる夜
Poor acting only hypes up the night.
息が耳に触れた二人 Ah
As our breath brushes our ears, the two of us, ah...
ABC 続かない
We can't even get past ABC.
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
That's no good, is it?
だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
あたしの青春
My youth
そんなもんじゃない
is not just some trivial thing.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn hot deep inside.
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it.
あたし イケナイ太陽
I am the bad sun.
Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na
Hoo... Hoo...
交わす言葉の記憶遠く
Memories of the words we exchange fade away,
口元の動きに揺れ動く
wavering with the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then, ah...
ABC ABC 続かない
ABC, ABC, it doesn't continue.
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
That's no good, is it?
だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない？
Because deep down in your heart, isn't it different?
オレの青春
My youth
そんなもんじゃない
is not just some trivial thing.
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn hot deep inside.
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it.
オレは イケナイ太陽
I am the bad sun.
絡み合う糸は
The tangled threads,
君と俺を結ぶ赤い糸
are the red thread of fate binding you and me.
Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na
あ、やばい！あははは！
Oh my gosh, that was close! Ahahaha!
いぇーい！
Yay!
いや、この曲番長のセクシーが溢れてていいですね！
Wow, Bancho's sexiness was totally overflowing in that song!
いや、ちょっとね、あっちっちになりましたね。
Yeah, it got pretty hot in here.
あっちっち！
So hot!
激アツ！社長の動きも激アツでした。
Super hot! The president's moves were super hot too.
やばい！おジョジョちゃんも。
Oh my gosh, and Jojo too!
おジョジョちゃん。踊り狂ってね。
Jojo was dancing like crazy!
楽しかったです！
It was so fun!
急にあの平成ですね、さっきから。
It's suddenly felt so "Heisei era" since a bit ago.
夏のバイブスというか、出たばっかりだからね、Midsummer Citrus。
Talk about summer vibes, especially since "Midsummer Citrus" just dropped.
あー、体動かしたくなってきたな！
Ah, now I really want to move my body too!
そういう感じの選曲も続きますよ、ということで。
And with that, we'll keep going with songs of that vibe!
かなで、らでの番なんじゃないの？
Isn't it Kanade and Raden's turn?
えー？いいじゃん。
Eh? Sure.
ちょっとこう、結構ね、ヒートアップしちゃったから
We've gotten a bit heated up,
一旦クールダウンしようかね
so let's cool down for a bit.
そうしよっか！らでの体力も持ちませんから！
Let's do that! Otherwise Raden's stamina won't hold up!
ちょっとゆったりした曲をね、いこうかね。そうだね。
Let's go with a more relaxing song. "Right."
はい、じゃあ2人とも準備してくださいね。はーい！
Alright, you two please get ready. "Okay!"
はーい。はーい。よいしょっと。
Okay. Okay. Up we go.
準備できた？はい！
Are you ready? "Yes!"
あれ、座って歌う？いや、立つ！
Wait, are you sitting to sing? "No, I'm standing!"
あ、立つのかな？立つのか！
Oh, she's standing? "She is!"
立った！立った！心も立ってきた！
She stood! She stood! My heart's standing up too!
では、音楽おねがいします！踊っちゃだめよ？<
Now, music please! No dancing, okay?
プラネタリウム
[Planetarium]
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく 子供の声
The evening moon shows its face, and the children's voices fade away...
遠く遠く この空のどこかに 君はいるんだろう
Far, far away, somewhere in this sky, you must be there.
夏の終わりに 2人で抜け出した
At the end of summer, the two of us snuck out...
この公園で見つけた
...and in this park, we found...
あの星座 何だか 覚えいる?
...that constellation. Do you remember what it was?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories...
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
...wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
wanting to run to you right now.
まっ暗で 何も 見えない 怖くても 大丈夫
It's pitch black and I can't see, but it's okay to be scared.
数えきれない 星空が
The countless stars in the night sky...
今も ずっと ここにあるんだよ
...are still here, even now.
泣かないよ 昔 君と見た
I won't cry, because it's the beautiful sky...
きれいな 空だったから
...that I looked at with you back then.
あの道まで 響く
Echoing all the way to that street,
靴の音が 耳に残る
the sound of your shoes remains in my ears.
大きな 自分の影を 見つめて 想うのでしょう
You must be thinking of it too as you look at your large shadow.
ちっとも 変わらない はずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed,
せつない気持ち ふくらんでく
a painful feeling swells up inside me.
どんなに想ったって 君は もういない
No matter how much I long for you, you're already gone.
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go and be by your side,
小さくても 小さくても
even if I am small, even if I am small...
1番に 君が好きだよ 強く いられる
I love you more than anyone, and it makes me strong.
願いを 流れ星に
I tried to make a quiet wish...
そっと 唱えて みたけれど
...on a shooting star,
泣かないよ 届くだろう
but I won't cry, I'm sure it will reach...
きれいな 空に
...that beautiful sky.
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories...
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
...wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
小さな手をにぎりしめて
holding your tiny hand tight.
泣きたいよ それはそれは
I want to cry, it was such a...
きれいなそらだった
...beautiful sky.
願いを流れ星に
I tried whispering my wish to a shooting star...
そっと唱えてみたけれど
...but even though I did,
泣きたいよ 届かない
I want to cry, because my unreachable feelings...
想いをこの空に...
...are cast into this sky...
イェーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
すご！ハイタッチ！ハイタッチ、マジで！
Awesome! High five! Seriously, high five!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ごめん！
Sorry!
ちょっと悲しいハイタッチになっちゃった
That was a bit of a sad high five.
はい、プラネタリウムでした！
And that was "Planetarium"!
すごかったー！
That was amazing!
もうこれライブパフォーマンスやん、マジで
Seriously, that was like a live concert performance!
最高すぎるやろ
It was just too good!
もう一回聴きたい！
I want to hear it again!
ちょっと、あの、体力がない...
I, uh, don't have the stamina...
体力かー
Ah, stamina.
じゃあ、奏、歌う？一緒に
Then, Kanade, do you want to sing together?
いいよ！やったー！
Sure! Yay!
みんな、何歌う？何歌う？
What should we sing, everyone?
乗ろう、乗ろう！あの曲行っちゃいますか！
Let's get into it! Should we go with THAT song?
おっ、何？何？
Oh? What is it? What is it?
何だろう？なんだと思う？
I wonder what it is? What do you think?
やっぱり、お星様がキラキラしたら、もう一回キラキラしたいんじゃないの？
I mean, since the stars were shining, shouldn't we shine once more?
なるほど、なるほど！プラネタリウムから外に出ちゃう？
I see, I see! Are we stepping outside of the planetarium?
天体観測！それ！
Astronomical Observation! That's the one!
何の曲かなー？
I wonder what song it is...
じゃあ行きましょう！お願いしまーす！
Then let's do it! Here we go!
どっちからだっけ？えっ、どっちからだっけ？奏で！
Who starts first? Uh, who starts first? Kanade!
午前二時 フミキリに
At 2:00 AM, at the railroad crossing,
望遠鏡を担いでった
I carried my telescope.
ベルトに結んだラジオ
With the radio tied to my belt,
雨は降らないらしい
it seemed like it wouldn't rain.
二分後に君が来た
Two minutes later, you arrived,
大袈裟な荷物しょって来た
carrying an exaggerated amount of luggage.
始めようか 天体観測
Shall we begin our astronomical observation,
ほうき星を探して
searching for a comet?
深い闇に飲まれないように
Trying our best not to get swallowed
精一杯だった
by the deep darkness.
君の震える手を
Trying to hold your trembling hand
握ろうとしたあの日は
on that day...
見えないモノを見ようとして
Trying to see the invisible,
望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
we peered into the telescope.
静寂を切り裂いて
Ripping through the silence,
いくつも声が生まれたよ
countless voices were born.
明日が僕らを呼んだって
Even if tomorrow called out to us,
返事もろくにしなかった
we barely gave it an answer.
「イマ」というほうき星
Chasing after that comet
君と二人追いかけていた
called "The Present" together.
気が付けばいつだって
Before we knew it, we were always
ひたすら何か探している
searching for something.
幸せの定義とか
The definition of happiness,
哀しみの置き場とか
or where to put our sadness...
生まれたら死ぬまで
From the moment we are born until we die,
ずっと探してる
we are always searching.
さぁ 始めようか 天体観測
Now, shall we begin our astronomical observation,
ほうき星を探して
searching for a comet?
今まで見つけたモノは
Everything we've found so far,
全部覚えている
I remember it all.
君の震える手を
Even the pain of not being able
握れなかった痛みも
to hold your trembling hand.
知らないモノを知ろうとして
Trying to know the unknown,
望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
we peered into the telescope.
暗闇を照らす様な
Searching for a faint light
微かな光 探したよ
that would light up the darkness.
そうして知った痛みを
The pain that we learned back then,
未だに僕は覚えている
I still remember it even now.
「イマ」というほうき星
Chasing after that comet
今も一人追いかけている
called "The Present" all alone now.
背が伸びるにつれて
As I grew taller, the things
伝えたい事も増えてった
I wanted to tell you grew too.
宛名の無い手紙も
Even the unaddressed letters
崩れる程重なった
piled up so high they collapsed.
僕は元気でいるよ
I am doing well,
心配事も少ないよ
and I don't have many worries.
ただひとつ 今も思い出すよ
It's just that there's one thing I still remember...
予報外れの雨に
Drenched by the unexpected rain,
打たれて泣きだしそうな
as if you were about to cry...
君の震える手を
That day when I couldn't hold
握れなかった あの日を
your trembling hand...
見えてるモノを見落として
Overlooking the things right in front of us,
望遠鏡をまた担いで
I shouldered my telescope once again.
静寂と暗闇の帰り道を駆け抜けた
I ran through the silence and darkness on the way home.
そうして知った痛みが
And the pain I felt then...
帰り道を駆け抜けた
...I ran through the way home.
そうして知った痛みが 未だに僕を支えている
And the pain I learned then still supports me.
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
A comet named "Now," I'm still chasing it alone.
もう一度君に会おうとして 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Hoping to meet you once again, I shoulder my telescope once more.
前と同じ午前二時 フミキリまで駆けてくよ
At 2:00 AM, just like before, I'll run to the railroad crossing.
始めようか天体観測 二分後に君が来なくとも
Let's begin our astronomical observation, even if you don't show up in two minutes.
「イマ」というほうき星 君と二人追いかけている
A comet named "Now," we are both chasing it together.
はあー、疲れた
Ah, that was tiring!
めっちゃ踊ってくれた
You danced so much!
踊ってたっていうかパフォーマンス？
More of a performance than dancing!
違う、体が勝手に...
No, my body just moved on its own...
二人でね、ほうき星探しに行ってくれたんだよね。ちょっとね
You two went looking for the comet together, didn't you? A little bit, yeah.
あー、疲れたね
Ah, I'm so tired.
めっちゃ歩き回っちゃった。歩き回ってたね
I ended up walking around a lot! You sure were!
全員、ちょっとヘトヘト...
Everyone is a bit exhausted...
はじめはもう一曲目からヘトヘトですけど
We're exhausted from just the first song, but...
でもね、このままちょっとらでんと番長の二人を聴きたいな、なんて思ってるんですけども
But you know, I really want to hear Raden and Bancho sing next!
いいよ！いい？
Sure! Is it okay?
徒歩じゃなくて チャリで駆け上がりますか
Instead of walking, shall we climb up on a bike?
チャリで。行きましょう。行ってらっしゃい
On a bike. Let's do it! Good luck!
はい、じゃあ準備いいですか？
Alright, are you ready?
OK。はい、じゃあ音楽お願いします
Okay. Music please!
きた、夏色！
Here it is, Natsuiro!
夏といえばこれでしょう！
This is the ultimate summer song!
チャリン、チャリン、チャリン...
Ring ring, ring ring...
駐車場のネコはアクビをしながら
The cat in the parking lot yawns,
今日も一日を過ごしてゆく
and spends another day like this.
何も変わらない 穏やかな街並み
In a quiet town where nothing ever changes.
みんな夏が来たって浮かれ気分なのに
Even though everyone is excited that summer has arrived,
君は一人さええない顔してるね
you have such a gloomy expression all by yourself.
そうだ君に 見せたい物があるんだ
That's right, there is something I want to show you.
大きな五時半の夕やけ
A grand sunset at 5:30,
子供の頃と同じように
just like when we were children.
海も空も雲も 僕等でさえも
The sea, the sky, the clouds, and even us...
染めてゆくから...
...are being painted by it.
この長い長い下り坂を 君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
Riding a bicycle down this long, long slope with you on the back,
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
gripping the brakes tight...
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
...and going down slowly, slowly.
下ってくよー
Going down!
うおー！
Whoa!
風鈴の音でウトウトしながら
Dozing off to the sound of wind chimes,
夢見ごこちでヨダレをたらしてる
dreamily drooling a little bit.
いつもと同じ 網戸ごしの風の匂い
Always the same smell of wind through the screen door.
休日でみんなもゴロゴロしてるのに
Even though everyone is lounging around on their day off,
君はずいぶん忙しい顔をしてるね
you have quite a busy expression.
そうだいつかのあの場所へ行こう
That's right, let's go to that place sometime.
真夏の夜の波の音は
The sound of the waves on a midsummer night
不思議な程心静かになる
mysteriously calms my heart.
少しだけ全て忘れて 波の音の中包み込まれてゆく
Forget everything for a little while, wrapped in the sound of the waves.
この細い細い裏道を抜けて
Slipping through this narrow, narrow backstreet,
誰もいない大きな夜の海見ながら
looking at the grand night sea with no one else around.
線香花火に二人で ゆっくりゆっくり火をつける
Lighting sparklers together, slowly, slowly lighting the fire.
いつか君の涙が こぼれおちそうになったら
Someday, if your tears are about to fall...
何もしてあげられないけど 少しでもそばにいるよ
...I can't do much for you, but I'll be by your side.
この長い長い下り坂を 君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
Riding a bicycle down this long, long slope with you on the back,
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
gripping the brakes tight,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
going down slowly, slowly.
Going down slowly, slowly.
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
夏だね！夏が始まった！チャリン、チャリン、最高！
It's summer! Summer has begun! Ring ring, awesome!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
にゃー！
Yaay!
じゃあちょっと連続なんですけど
Well, it's back-to-back, but...
おっ
Oh!
最後 4 人で歌いたいと思います！
Lastly, we want to sing as the four of us!
おー！何歌うんですか？
Oh! What are we going to sing?
何歌うんだろうね？
What will we sing, I wonder?
じゃあ皆さん聴いてください！おねがいします！
Well then, everyone, please listen! Here we go!
ウィーーアーー！
We Are!
富、名声、力
Wealth, fame, power.
この世のすべてを手に入れた男、海賊王ゴールド・ロジャー
The man who had acquired everything in this world, the Pirate King, Gold Roger.
彼の死に際に放った一言は、人々を海へ駆り立てた
The words he uttered at his death drove people to the seas.
「俺の財宝か？欲しけりゃくれてやる。探せ！この世のすべてをそこに置いてきた！」
"My treasure? If you want it, you can have it. Look for it! I left everything this world has to offer there!"
男たちは、グランドラインを目指し
Men head for the Grand Line...
夢を追い続ける。世はまさに、大海賊時代！
...and continue to pursue their dreams. The world is truly in the Great Pirate Era!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams,
捜し物を捜しに 行くのさ
we're going to search for everything we're looking for.
ONE PIECE
羅針盤なんて 渋滞のもと
A compass will only slow us down.
熱にうかされ 舵をとるのさ
Filled with excitement, I take the helm.
ホコリかぶってた 宝の地図も
If we can prove the dusty old treasure map,
確かめたのなら 伝説じゃない！
then it won't be a legend anymore!
個人的な嵐は 誰かの
It's alright if our internal storms
バイオリズム乗っかって 思い過ごせばいい！
get on someone else's nerves, because we think about them too much!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams,
捜し物を捜しに 行くのさ
we're going to search for everything we're looking for.
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A coin in the pocket, and "You wanna be my friend?"
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
よっしゃー！いい感じ！
Yes! Looking good!
ぜんぶまに受けて 信じちゃっても
Even though I believe everything they tell me,
肩を押されて 1歩リードさ
if you push me on the shoulder, I'm one step ahead.
今度会えたなら 話すつもりさ
If we ever meet again, I'll tell you all about
それからのことと これからのこと
what I've been doing and where I'm headed next.
つまりいつもピンチは 誰かに
In other words, being in a pinch is always
アピール出来る いいチャンス
a good opportunity to ask for backup
自意識過剰に！
and overcome one's excessive shyness!
しみったれた夜を ぶっとばせ！
Full steam ahead through the stingy night!
宝箱にキョウミは ないけれど
I'm not interested in treasure anyway,
ポケットにロマン それと You wanna be my Friend?
but a romance in my pocket, and "You wanna be my friend?"
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams,
捜し物を捜しに 行くのさ
we're going to search for everything we're looking for.
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A coin in the pocket, and "You wanna be my friend?"
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ウィーアー！ ウィーアー！ ウィーアー！
We are! We are! We are!
やばい、もう時間だ、時間だ！最後にお知らせがあります！
Oh no, time's already up, time's up! Lastly, we have some announcements!
明日0時、つまり今日の24時に「Midsummer Citrus」がデジタルリリースされます！
Tomorrow at midnight, meaning at 24:00 today, "Midsummer Citrus" will be released digitally!
いぇーい！
Yay!
こちらは後4時間後ぐらいかな、聴けるようになります！
You'll be able to listen to it in about 4 hours!
そして、来月の配信なんですが、いつも10日にReGLOSSのこの配信をやってるんですけれど
Also, about next month's stream, we usually stream ReGLOSS on the 10th, but...
8月は8月1日に配信予定となっております。間違えないように注意してください！
in August, it's scheduled for August 1st. Please make sure not to make a mistake!
1日！よろしくね！
On the 1st! Please look forward to it!
楽しかったね、カラオケ！カラオケとは思えない...
That karaoke was fun! I can't believe it's karaoke...
もうもがくだけだけどね。
But we're just struggling, right?
全力でした！
I gave it my all!
美味しいもの食べるため。そうね。
To eat delicious food. Yeah, that's right.
見てくれたみんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
I hope everyone watching had fun too!
楽しかった！
It was so fun!
たくさんのアンケートの回答もありがとうございました！
And thank you so much for answering all the surveys!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、じゃあ今日はこんなとこで終わりますか。
Okay, shall we wrap it up here for today?
はーい！
Yes!
それではまた来月お会いしましょう！見てくれてありがとうね！
Well then, see you next month! Thanks for watching!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
新曲披露もあるよ！真夏のReGLOSSカラオケ
Midsummer ReGLOSS Karaoke (New Song Reveal Too!)